<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1"
         xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
         packageId="aacd816d-662c-49d2-ad1a-97e66e2a2908/v393.209" system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
         xml:lang="eng">

<dataset>
  <alternateIdentifier>aacd816d-662c-49d2-ad1a-97e66e2a2908</alternateIdentifier>
  <alternateIdentifier>http://ipt.jbrj.gov.br/jbrj/resource?r=lista_especies_flora_brasil</alternateIdentifier>
  <title xml:lang="eng">Brazilian Flora 2020 project - Projeto Flora do Brasil 2020</title>
      <creator>
    <individualName>
        <givenName>Group</givenName>
      <surName>Brazil Flora</surName>
    </individualName>
    <organizationName>REFLORA Program</organizationName>
    <positionName>Authors</positionName>
    <address>
        <deliveryPoint>Rua Pacheco Leão 915</deliveryPoint>
        <city>Rio de Janeiro</city>
        <administrativeArea>RJ</administrativeArea>
        <postalCode>22460-030</postalCode>
        <country>BR</country>
    </address>
    <phone>+552132042082</phone>
    <electronicMailAddress>floradobrasil2020@jbrj.gov.br</electronicMailAddress>
    <onlineUrl>http://floradobrasil.jbrj.gov.br</onlineUrl>
      </creator>
      <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
        <givenName>Group</givenName>
      <surName>Brazil Flora</surName>
    </individualName>
    <organizationName>REFLORA Program</organizationName>
    <positionName>Authors</positionName>
    <address>
        <deliveryPoint>Rua Pacheco Leão 915</deliveryPoint>
        <city>Rio de Janeiro</city>
        <administrativeArea>RJ</administrativeArea>
        <postalCode>22460-030</postalCode>
        <country>BR</country>
    </address>
    <phone>+552132042082</phone>
    <electronicMailAddress>floradobrasil2020@jbrj.gov.br</electronicMailAddress>
    <onlineUrl>http://floradobrasil.jbrj.gov.br</onlineUrl>
      </metadataProvider>
  <pubDate>
      2019-10-30
  </pubDate>
  <language>por</language>
  <abstract>
    <para>In 2010, Brazil published the Catalog of Plants and Fungi of Brazil and launched the first online version of the List of Species of the Brazilian Flora, meeting Target 1 of the Global Strategy for Plant Conservation (GSPC-CBD). This botanical milestone was only achieved due to the commitment of more than 400  Brazilians and foreign taxonomists who worked on a platform where information about our flora was included and disseminated in real time. The &quot;Brazilian List&quot;, as it was popularly known, closed in November 2015 with the publication of five papers and their respective databases (see Download as above) dealing with the different groups of fungi and plants. We enthusiastically present, in 2016, the brand new system that houses the Brazilian Flora 2020 project, aiming to achieve Target 1 established for 2020 by the GSPC-CBD. This new project icludes provisions to include descriptions, identification keys and illustrations to all species of plants, algae and fungi known in the country. The Brazilian Flora 2020 project is part of the Reflora Programme and is being conducted with the support of the Sistema de Informação sobre a Biodiversidade Brasileira (SiBBr). At the moment has nearly 700 scientists working in a network to prepare the monographs. These researchers are also responsible for nomenclatural information and geographic distribution (coverage in Brazil, endemism and biomes), as well as valuable data regarding life forms, substrate and vegetation types for each species. The search results on this page include information on endangered species (thanks to the cooperation with the Centro Nacional de Conservação da Flora) and allow access to the Index Herbariorum (due to the collaboration of The New York Botanical Garden). Besides this information, users can also access images of herbarium specimens, including nomenclatural types, from both the Reflora Virtual Herbarium and INCT Virtual Herbarium of Flora and Fungi; as well as images of live plants and scientific illustrations with all images included by the experts in each group.

To date (2018-02-06), 46485 species are recognized for Brazil&apos;s flora: 4754 Algae, 33087 Angiosperms, 1567 Bryophytes, 5718 Fungi, 30 Gymnosperms and 1329 Ferns and Lycophytes.</para>
  </abstract>
      <keywordSet>
            <keyword>Checklist</keyword>
        <keywordThesaurus>GBIF Dataset Type Vocabulary: http://rs.gbif.org/vocabulary/gbif/dataset_type.xml</keywordThesaurus>
      </keywordSet>
      <keywordSet>
            <keyword>Inventoryregional</keyword>
        <keywordThesaurus>GBIF Dataset Subtype Vocabulary: http://rs.gbif.org/vocabulary/gbif/dataset_subtype.xml</keywordThesaurus>
      </keywordSet>
  <intellectualRights>
    <para>This work is licensed under a <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode"><citetitle>Creative Commons Attribution (CC-BY) 4.0 License</citetitle></ulink>.</para>
  </intellectualRights>
  <distribution scope="document">
    <online>
      <url function="information">http://floradobrasil.jbrj.gov.br/</url>
    </online>
  </distribution>
  <coverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
          <geographicDescription>Brazil</geographicDescription>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-180</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>180</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>90</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>-90</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
  </coverage>
  <maintenance>
    <description>
      <para></para>
    </description>
    <maintenanceUpdateFrequency>weekly</maintenanceUpdateFrequency>
  </maintenance>

      <contact>
    <individualName>
        <givenName>Group</givenName>
      <surName>Brazil Flora</surName>
    </individualName>
    <organizationName>REFLORA Program</organizationName>
    <positionName>Authors</positionName>
    <address>
        <deliveryPoint>Rua Pacheco Leão 915</deliveryPoint>
        <city>Rio de Janeiro</city>
        <administrativeArea>RJ</administrativeArea>
        <postalCode>22460-030</postalCode>
        <country>BR</country>
    </address>
    <phone>+552132042082</phone>
    <electronicMailAddress>floradobrasil2020@jbrj.gov.br</electronicMailAddress>
    <onlineUrl>http://floradobrasil.jbrj.gov.br</onlineUrl>
      </contact>
</dataset>
  <additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
          <dateStamp>2014-04-16T02:42:50.854-03:00</dateStamp>
          <hierarchyLevel>dataset</hierarchyLevel>
            <citation identifier="doi:10.15468/1mtkaw">Brazil Flora G (2019): Brazilian Flora 2020 project - Projeto Flora do Brasil 2020. v393.209. Instituto de Pesquisas Jardim Botanico do Rio de Janeiro. Dataset/Checklist. doi:10.15468/1mtkaw</citation>
          <bibliography>
                <citation identifier="http://reflora.jbrj.gov.br/downloads/vol1.pdf">FORZZA, R. C., BAUMGRATZ, J. F., Bicudo, C.E.M., CARVALHO JUNIOR, A., COSTA, Andréa, COSTA, D. P., HOPKINS, M. J. G., LEITMAN, P., LOHMANN, L. G., MAIA, L. C., MARTINELLI, G., MENEZES, M., Morim, M. P., COELHO, M. N., PEIXOTO, A. L., PIRANI, J. R., PRADO, J., Queiroz, L.P., Souza, V. C., STEHMANN, J., SYLVESTRE, Lana, Walter, B.M.T., ZAPPI, D. Catálogo das Plantas e Fungos do Brasil. Rio de Janeiro : Andrea Jakobsson Estúdio &amp; Jardim Botânico do Rio de Janeiro, 2010, v. 1 e 2. p.1699.</citation>
                <citation identifier="http://reflora.jbrj.gov.br/downloads/FUNG1.pdf">Forzza, Rafaela C., Baumgratz, José Fernando A., Bicudo, Carlos Eduardo M., Canhos, Dora A. L., Carvalho, Anibal A., Coelho, Marcus A. Nadruz, Costa, Andrea F., Costa, Denise P., Hopkins, Michael G., Leitman, Paula M., Lohmann, Lucia G., Lughadha, Eimear Nic, Maia, Leonor Costa, Martinelli, Gustavo, Menezes, Mariângela, Morim, Marli Pires, Peixoto, Ariane Luna, Pirani, José R., Prado, Jefferson, Queiroz, Luciano P., Souza, Sidnei, Souza, Vinicius Castro, Stehmann, João R., Sylvestre, Lana S., Walter, Bruno M. T., Zappi, Daniela C. New Brazilian Floristic List Highlights Conservation Challenges. Bioscience (Washington. Print). , v.62, p.39 - 45, 2012.</citation>
                <citation identifier="http://ckan.jbrj.gov.br/dataset/floradobrasil">MENEZES, M. et al. Update of the Brazilian floristic list of Algae and Cyanobacteria. Rodriguésia, v. 66, n. 4, 2015. (DOI: 10.1590 / 2175-7860201566408)</citation>
                <citation identifier="http://ckan.jbrj.gov.br/dataset/floradobrasil">BFG. Growing knowledge: an overview of Seed Plant diversity in Brazil. Rodriguesia, v. 66, n. 4, 2015. (DOI: 10.1590/2175-7860201566411)</citation>
                <citation identifier="http://ckan.jbrj.gov.br/dataset/floradobrasil">COSTA, D. P.; PERALTA, D. F. Bryophytes diversity in Brazil. Rodriguésia, v. 66, n. 4, p. 1–9, 2015. (DOI: 10.1590 / 2175-7860201566409)</citation>
                <citation identifier="http://ckan.jbrj.gov.br/dataset/floradobrasil">MAIA, L. C. et al. Diversity of Brazilian Fungi. Rodriguésia, v. 66, n. November, 2015. (DOI: 10.1590 / 2175-7860201566407)</citation>
                <citation identifier="http://ckan.jbrj.gov.br/dataset/floradobrasil">PRADO, J. et al. Diversity of ferns and lycophytes in Brazil. Rodriguésia, v. 66, n. 4, 2015. (DOI: 10.1590 / 2175-7860201566410)</citation>
          </bibliography>
          <resourceLogoUrl>http://ipt.jbrj.gov.br/jbrj/logo.do?r=lista_especies_flora_brasil</resourceLogoUrl>
          <dc:replaces>aacd816d-662c-49d2-ad1a-97e66e2a2908/v393.209.xml</dc:replaces>
      </gbif>
    </metadata>
  </additionalMetadata>
</eml:eml>
